# **MICHAEL J COLLINS**

Mobile: +61 412 567 589

Email: mich.collins1@gmail.com Linkedin: michaeljamescollins96

Github: Mikephii

## PERSONAL SUMMARY

I'm an engineer who loves to learn and invent. I previously worked for AusMed Global as lead product engineer, where I helped invent the core technology and algorithms supporting a consumer medical device for the detection and measurement of breath ketones. I was awarded inventorship of our subsequently filed patent: "Systems, sensors and methods for determining a concentration of an analyte,". I am passionate about using software to affect change in tangible real-world applications. After working with Python and MATLAB for 3 years, I have taught myself modern JavaScript frameworks over the past 12 months so that I can better apply myself to the current software landscape in Australia. I believe I can provide real value to your team due to my deep technical background, rapid learning abilities and creative outlook. I love to work in teams, and nothing feels better than working in a team that is united in our passion for solving a common goal.

## **SKILLS**

#### Tech

JavaScript, Python, MATLAB, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, ReactRedux

#### **Tools**

Git, Microsoft Office, Firestore, FaunaDB, Fusion360, Photoshop, Arduino

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## AusMed Global - Lead Product Engineer (May 2018 - March 2021)

- Responsible for design of sensing algorithms and hardware for portable consumer medical device.
- Inventor of patent related to sensing methods and algorithms: "Systems, sensors and methods for determining a concentration of an analyte," Patent Application No. 2019336336.
- Multiple years' experience using Python and MATLAB for sensing algorithms and data analysis.

## Antler early-stage VC start-up accelerator (July 2021-September 2021)

- Accepted into and participated in Antler Australia's early-stage start-up accelerator program as a JavaScript Developer (5th cohort)
- Founded and developed Phifinder using JavaScript based libraries NextJS, ExpressJS and Firestore as a part of Antler Australia's early-stage start-up accelerator.

# **MICHAEL J COLLINS**

Mobile: +61 412 567 589

Email: mich.collins1@gmail.com Linkedin: michaeljamescollins96

Github: Mikephii

## **EXPERIENCE CONT.**

# Zip Co Credit Analyst (March 2017-October 2018)

- Underwrite unsecured lines of credit up to \$40,000
- Analyse and detect fraudulent applications

## Zip Co Customer Service (March 2016-March 2017)

 Inbound and outbound point of call for customers, new and existing merchants/clients, for B2B operational training, debt collection and customer troubleshooting.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Sydney- Bachelor of Engineering Honours (Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering.)

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**Primary inventor of Australian Patent:** "Systems, sensors and methods for determining a concentration of an analyte," Australian Patent Application No. 2019336336. http://pericles.ipaustralia.gov.au/ols/auspat/applicationDetails.do?applicationNo=2019336336 #

University of Sydney - M. Phil (Integrated nano-photonic sensing) - Discontinued